Tom Preston

Date of birth: 16/01/1989 Address: Bristol, UK

Phone number: 07842203840

Email address: tom.preston377@gmail.com

Profile: www.tom-preston.co.uk Github: https://github.com/prestto

Profile

Software Developer with 7 years of experience (3 years Dev, 4 years Data Analysis). A Full Stack Engineer with a strong interest in DevOps and developing new and exciting projects. Held a a senior position in the R&D team at a successful startup, bringing MVPs to market, from conception to deployment.

Experience developing Machine Learning based products, specifically NLP solutions, Databases Design, Micro-service

Very familiar with the Agile methodology. Also comfortable creating Roadmaps, and separating projects into functional and technical elements, as well as being able to explain technical concepts to non-technical staff.

Good understanding of Search Engine concepts, implementation and configuration.

Skills

- LANGUAGES

Python SQL (Postgres, MSSQL) JavaScript TypeScript Bash R **VBA**



- FRAMEWORKS

ElasticSearch (and ELK stack) Django Django REST Angular 8+



- DEVOPS

Docker **Docker Compose** Kubernetes Gitlab CI



Education

09/2011 - 01/2013 SWANSEA, WALES

Business Economics | MSc Swansea University

2008 - 2012 SWANSEA, WALES **Business Economics with Accounting | BA Swansea University**

Work experience

07/2018 - 10/2021 LYON, FRANCE

Digglerz Factory - Ingénieur Etudes et Développement (Engineer R&D)

Development of an on premises solution for deduplication, tagging and cleansing data. Jimare was created to assist the buying teams at a multinational builder/ building supplier by using a machine learning algorithm to classify products and suppliers to an internal taxonomy. Entities were deduplicated, and the quality of data improved, enabling their subsidiaries to benefit from price arbitrage.

Stack: Django REST, Docker, Docker compose, Bash, ElasticSearch Angular, TypeScript, HTML, SCSS

Kapsule.ai

A project focused on offline search, Kapsule allows a business to combine a search engine, config and data into an easy to use package. This was beneficial for companies needing reliable access to their data (in remote locations, or where risk of internet failure was unacceptable). It would also benefit online ecommerce companies with a high request and relatively small product catalogue.

Stack: Django REST, Docker, Docker compose, Bash, Angular, TypeScript, HTML, SCSS

POC to demonstrate usefulness the of ElasticSearch to help with track selection for a french radio station software. Stack: ElasticSearch, JavaScript, Django, HTML, CSS

06/2016 - 07/2018 LYON, FRANCE

Data Analyst

Statistical analysis of fraud at national and company level. Detection, monitoring and reporting of Interconnect fraud for mobile operators allowed disconnection of fraudulent SIMs.

07/2014 - 10/2015 MILTON KEYNES, UK

Data Analyst

Argos

Forecasting the workload for a distribution network of 30000 products and 5000 people. Creation of Annual, monthly and weekly workload forecast for volumes. Creation of Database to manage inter warehouse stock transfers and cleansing of existing data. Maintaining and automating existing reporting.

Achievements

Ironman Nice 2018 (140.6) SaintéLyon Ultra marathon Fluent French